[guests chattering]
Is that her?
The incomparable
who captured the prince's eye.
A mere wisp of a young lady,
and a commoner at that.
Everyone seems to have quite an opinion.
[chuckles]
How long do you think it will be
before Her Majesty arrives?
I may very well faint from hunger.
Mama! We are at court!
No one is looking at me, dearest.
Mama!
That's quite delicious. [laughs]
My darling, you seem a little strained.
You have been that way
for the past few days.
-I have much on my mind.
-You do, indeed.
[doors open]
Her Majesty Queen Charlotte
and her esteemed nephew,
Prince Friedrich of Prussia.
[regal music plays]
Miss Bridgerton, I find myself in raptures
over your acceptance
of my invitation to the palace.
You flatter me, Your Highness.
I cannot help it.
You are perfection itself.
Offer her your gift.
I have brought you a gift.
[exclaims softly]
[guests gasp, murmur]
[mournful piano music plays]
[Daphne sighs, echoing]
[Daphne gasps]
Miss Bridgerton, are you unwell?
I am perfectly well. Of course.
[breathes tremulously]
This necklace is…
quite well too.
She will make a lovely princess,
will she not?
Of course, Your Majesty.
[chuckles softly]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">In a town filled with ambitious mamas
and fortune-hunting gentlemen,
marrying above one's station
is an art form, indeed.
But Miss Daphne Bridgerton's advance
from future duchess to possible princess
is an achievement
that even this jaded author must applaud.
Is it true?
Am I to be the sister of a princess?
Calm yourself.
I am not yet engaged to the prince.
Will you have to wear a crown?
Perhaps for special occasions,
but only if I should marry the prince.
-Will you have to learn Prussian?
-It is German.
And perhaps,
but only if I should marry the prince.
Will you have to move
to a castle far, far away?
Should you not be off somewhere
with your governess?
I should. My governess has
the very same questions as me!
[sighs sharply]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Though this author cannot dismiss
the Duke of Hastings quite so soon.
He may have let the diamond
slip through his fingers for now,
but I shall wager he is not a man
to ever hide from a fight.
[Simon grunting rapidly]
Does that sack of grain
have a German accent,
or is it my imagination?
Remind me, Will…
are you participating
in a boxing exhibition today,
or is it a comedy exhibition?
-I was afraid you had forgotten.
-I had not.
Although I am afraid
you will have to soldier on
without your greatest admirer present
this afternoon.
Alice will be present.
I am leaving England. [panting]
My business is concluded.
Will's is not.
This will be
the biggest match of my career.
-I am not favored to win it.
-Will--
Your smart friends know
you frequent my saloon.
Who will wager on me
if you are not present?
I don't have any friends.
How about after the Irishman today, Will,
you pummel the piss
out of His Grace's self-pity?
I have never asked a favor,
but I implore you not to miss this match.
His Grace would like to miss
the chance of seeing the Bridgerton girl
on the arm of a prince.
Perhaps you're right.
Both of you understand
I am just here, do you?
I am not nearly as devoted
as the two of you,
along with Lady Whistledown,
would like to believe.
The only thing we are devoted to
is putting food in our children's mouths.
Perhaps you'd like to dig
a little deeper today, Your Grace,
and help us fatten
the match organizer's purses
as well as ours?
What?
You don't love me for my subtlety.
[Simon sighs]
[horse neighing]
[grunts]
Her needlework is divine.
And, of course, she sings
and plays the pianoforte very prettily.
Show me a smile, girl.
I beg your pardon?
Your teeth, I want to see them.
Is she simpleminded?
Goodness, no! Oh, you are droll!
Miss Thompson, um,
show Lord Rutledge your lovely smile.
-Miss Thompson?
-[Rutledge grunts]
Tell a lot from a person's mouth.
Soldiers' teeth.
Taken from the battlefield.
Cost a pretty penny, let me tell you.
I shall try her out in company,
see how she acquits herself.
Of course.
We will be attending the Trowbridge ball
this evening, naturally.
Oh, very well.
Good day, Featherington.
Rutledge.
You cannot be serious.
How dare you conduct yourself
in such brazen manner?
-Do you see now what I must endure daily?
-[Lord Featherington] Mm.
I have had suitors calling on me
every morning this week.
If you think
I'm going to marry that vile old--
Those suitors are courting you, my dear.
That could take weeks, months.
Even if a miracle occurred,
and one of them married you tomorrow,
how do you imagine
they would react six months hence
when that whelp of yours pops out
looking the picture of health?
Lord Rutledge is in want of an heir.
He will not ask questions.
[Marina huffs]
-[scoffs] She pushed me!
-No, she pushed me.
Hush, both of you! My nerves!
Marina?
Would you like me to stay in?
Kindly remind me, my lord,
why we cannot simply send Miss Thompson
back to her father in the country?
The matter is not for discussion.
A gentleman caller. Mr. Albion Finch.
Good day. [sneezes]
[gasps] Daisies always trouble my nose.
Miss Thompson is not receiving visitors,
Mr. Finch.
That is quite all right.
I am here to call on Miss Featherington.
Miss Philippa Featherington?
[exhales nervously]
Thank you, sir.
[chuckles]
[exhales contentedly]
I have never understood
the fashion for feathers in the hair.
Why would a woman want to draw notice
to the fact that she is like a bird
squawking for a man's attention
in some bizarre ritual?
Then why are we looking?
Because I would rather do anything
than stay a moment longer in that house
while everyone flutters around Daphne,
cooing over her prospects.
Is the prince still courting? I imagine
you cannot wait for the engagement.
Pen, once they are engaged,
I shall be next in line.
If anything,
I hope Daphne stays on the shelf forever.
She must marry eventually.
Why must our only options be
to squawk and settle
or to never leave the nest?
What if I want to fly?
[scoffs] You know who <span style="style2">is flying?
Lady Whistledown. She is up in the sky.
A brilliant woman of business
who fools the entire ton,
whilst pocketing their money.
Imagine the life she must lead.
Independence.
She is not simpering
on the edge of a ballroom every night,
praying a man might take a fancy
and leg-shackle her into marriage.
That is quite the life
you have imagined for her.
We must meet her
so that she might share her secrets
on how to avoid such a wretched,
uninteresting fate.
Lady Whistledown's identity
is quite protected.
Are we not the two most clever girls
in the ton?
If anyone can find her, it is us, I think.
If I could get out of any
of the week's events to help you, I would.
Pretend an illness.
Tell your mother
you caught whatever Marina had.
-How is she, by the way?
-Uh, recovering.
But it would be cruel of me
not to be by her side
when she comes back out.
I shall cheer you on
in your endeavors, though.
This one. I shall need a new quill
to make my list of suspects.
Ooh! Thank you.
[attendees clamoring]
[bookkeeper] Come on, then!
Is it Mondrich or Gillespie?
Thank you, sir!
[Daphne] If Mama knew
I were here, of all places…
[Anthony] Trust she would have
more to say to me than you.
There's your prince now.
With your fancy well in hand,
I shall make myself scarce
for the final blow.
Miss Bridgerton, I am delighted
to see you here today, though surprised.
Though I asked your brother to bring you
so we could spend some time together,
I admit I did not hold much hope.
Most ladies I have met cannot seem
to reconcile their delicate sensibilities
with the brutality of fights.
You must have no sisters, Your Highness,
if you think most women delicate and mild.
A trip to the modiste
during a silk shortage
would disabuse you
of such notions for good.
[both chuckle]
I suppose I have much to learn, then.
I would appreciate your expert tutelage
if you would join me.
[mournful music plays]
Miss Bridgerton?
Of course. I would be delighted.
Tell us, Mr. Mondrich, is it true
you've been training with the duke?
Let us not exaggerate my role.
I am a mere pupil.
-Target practice, at best.
-[Will] His Grace is modest.
He's one of the least pitiful students
I have ever trained.
[men laughing]
[Will] You'd do well following his lead
and wagering on me today.
Is that not right, Hastings?
-Hastings?
-Of course.
Our underdog, Mr. Mondrich,
shall emerge victorious.
I, for one,
have 40 shillings on Mr. Gillespie.
After all, he is the prince's man.
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
please take your seats!
-The match is to begin!
-[bell rings]
[crowd cheering, jeering]
[Simon] Watch him!
[crowd exclaims]
Fear not. My man is made of sterner stuff.
[Will groans]
-Yes, again!
-Come on, Mondrich! Watch your feet!
[playful music plays]
[music, no dialogue]
-[music ends]
-[crowd jeering loudly]
You must tell me, Your Highness,
do you miss your homeland?
I have never been to Prussia,
but I have read of its beauty.
It has attractions, to be sure.
That said,
I attended school here in England,
and I have often thought
there is no better place to live,
or to raise a family.
Uh, forgive me if I am too forthright,
but you have a great affinity
for your family, do you not?
I do. They are
the dearest thing in the world to me.
Are you close to yours?
I grew up
with many cousins running underfoot
and I believe I should like the same
for my children one day…
if my wife were amenable, of course.
[crowd cheers]
Come on, Billy!
Go on, Mondrich!
Focus, Mondrich! Get your wits about you!
Go on, Gillespie! Plant a facer!
Good man! Another!
[grunting]
[crowd cheers]
[Daphne exclaims]
[bell rings]
[crowd cheers loudly]
[Anthony] Go on, Mondrich!
[inaudible dialogue]
-[man] You guaranteed my money.
-Gentlemen!
I assure you, on my good name,
each of you will receive your payments.
I merely need two days to raise the blunt.
[men murmuring]
[Henry] What do you think, Bridgerton?
This one more to your liking?
Mr. Granville--
Perhaps they should take it
over to Somerset House
so it can be skyed right next to mine.
I believe I owe you an apology, sir.
Unnecessary.
I actually quite enjoy
the eloquent stings of your critique.
[Benedict] Mm.
So?
A touch morose for my tastes.
[Henry] Mm.
[Henry inhales]
A tragedy. The hound deserved better.
[laughs] Where is yours?
-My…
-Your work.
Are you to tell me
you're not an artist yourself?
Well, I-- I suppose sometimes I like to…
Well, I mean, I almost--
I believe "yes" and "thank you"
are the words you seek.
But either way,
you should come by my studio.
The pieces I do for myself are there,
and I think you will find
my real work far less, um…
Oh, how did you put it?
"Cold and lacking inner life"?
Mm. I shall never live that down, shall I?
-[chuckles]
-[Henry] Hmm.
[Benedict laughs]
I hear you are to leave town tonight.
You hear correctly.
I misjudged you.
I was never quite certain,
but now it is clear your intentions
with Daphne were honorable after all.
She has found herself a prince,
and you are going on your way.
Perhaps one day the two of us
will be able to laugh at all this?
Perhaps.
Are you to tell me
you're sorry to see me go?
We should not have
to go that far, should we?
[Simon chuckles]
Lord Bridgerton.
Your Highness.
I was told you would be here.
Might we have a word?
[Benedict] Certainly.
[inaudible dialogue]
Your brother took you where?
He kept close watch
the entire time, Mama.
It does not matter. A boxing exhibition
is no place for any young lady.
Is it a place for a prince?
Was he at today's match, Sister?
He certainly was.
It is a loathsome
and barbarous form of entertainment.
-What about the duke?
-[both] What about the duke?
Was he also present?
I do not know.
If the duke was there, I did not see him.
[playing classical piano tune]
-What are you writing?
-Nothing. [clears throat]
You sit about,
writing nothing all day long.
[sighs] I am telling Francesca
about what an officious
little busybody you are.
[chuckles ironically]
Mother. Daph.
Did you truly take your sister
to a boxing match?
Your admonishment will have to wait.
I have news.
Prince Friedrich has asked
for my permission to propose.
So soon?
Well, what did you tell him?
That I know better
than to answer for my sister.
I have no objections to the man.
People speak well of him.
Whatever you decide, Daph,
you shall have my support.
[tense music plays]
I… uh…
I… [sighs]
You need not decide now.
You have not known him long.
Let me know when you have an answer,
and I shall convey it.
Indeed.
It is quite a necklace. [chuckles]
Do you like it?
It is very beautiful.
But do you like it?
If you should have something to say,
Mama, please say it.
Well, I only wonder…
If you wear that necklace at
tonight's ball, what will the duke think?
Oh, Mama!
Until you have decided
to accept the prince's proposal,
I simply think
you should keep your mind open.
Mama, I do not care what the duke thinks.
Besides,
he will not even be at tonight's ball.
-What happened between the two of you?
-Nothing happened.
He is leaving.
I know my daughter.
I know it was not nothing between you.
You do not know.
You do not know anything.
Daphne, I know what I saw!
What you saw…
was a lie.
What?
It was a lie.
It was a ruse.
The… duke and I, we were pretending,
all so I could attract
a suitor of a high enough rank,
all so I could be that much more…
desirable.
It was an agreement.
It was an act, and it worked.
We got what we wanted.
You did, too. I now have a prince.
You should be proud.
What I wanted, dearest,
was for you to have the best,
not in terms of rank, but love.
And what I have seen
between you and the duke--
It was not real, Mama!
Everything you saw…
None of it was real.
Well, it…
It is over now.
[voice breaking]
I do not have to pretend any longer.
I am sorry, Mama.
I am so sorry. [sobs lightly]
It is a beautiful necklace.
I should like it very much.
[Lady Danbury]
I would tell you it's been lovely
spending all this time
with you, Your Grace,
but I tend to leave
such sycophantic behavior
for the rest of the ton.
I shall miss you, too, Lady Danbury.
Are you going to tell me
where you will go?
This time, that is.
I am still considering, but--
It does not really matter, does it?
I am sure you will abscond
to some remote corner of the world
and continue to do
what you have always done.
-And what would that be?
-Take everything you have for granted.
The young man
I have always taken pride in raising,
well…
I would have expected more.
More discernment,
more understanding, more appreciation.
Lady Danbury--
You allowed that young lady
to slip through your fingers
as if it were nothing.
I understand that you believe
such subjects as love and devotion,
affection and attachment,
you find it all trite and frivolous.
But have you any idea those very things
are precisely what have allowed
a new day to begin to dawn
in this society?
Look at our queen.
Look at our king. Look at their marriage.
Look at everything it is doing for us,
allowing us to become.
We were two separate societies,
divided by color,
until a king fell in love with one of us.
Love, Your Grace…
conquers all.
I believe that remains to be seen.
The king may have chosen his queen.
He may have elevated us
from novelties in their eyes
to now dukes and royalty,
and at that same whim…
he may just as easily change his mind,
a mind, as we all know, that is hanging on
by one very loose and tenuous thread.
So, no, I am sorry, Lady Danbury,
we are in disagreement here.
Love changes nothing.
My ship departs at quarter past nine.
I will write to you…
from wherever I go.
["Second Waltz"
by Dmitri Shostakovich plays]
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">As we all know,
there is nothing this author loves
more than a scandal,
and tonight's soiree promises
more than its fair share,
courtesy of the recently widowed
Lady Trowbridge.
Some may call
her celebrations too provocative,
and I would caution any young lady
from getting caught up
in the sensual nature of her fêtes.
For one scandalous move
between an unwed couple,
a wayward touch, or heaven forbid, a kiss,
would banish any young lady
from society in a trail of ruin.
Lord Rutledge.
Miss Thompson
has spent all afternoon telling us
how eager she is to converse with you.
I don't need her conversation.
I shall like to see how she spins.
[sneezes]
-Mr. Finch.
-Pardon me, Miss Featherington.
-[chuckles]
-Oh! What a delectable frock!
Almost the exact shade
of double Gloucester
your mother served at tea this afternoon.
I so love cheese.
-As do I, Mr. Finch. [chuckles]
-[laughs]
Though, I must say,
I do prefer a Stilton to a cheddar.
-[Albion chuckles]
-Mm!
Perhaps we will have two weddings
this season, my lord.
Oh, I do doubt that.
Daphne! [chuckles]
-You look beautiful, as always.
-Thank you, Cressida.
You could have chosen anyone.
You have gentlemen lined up
to pay you tribute.
Yet you did not hesitate to steal
my chance for happiness away, did you?
I knew the marriage market
would make rivals of us,
but I never thought you capable
of being my enemy.
The man made his choice, Cressida.
What did you expect me to do?
Miss Bridgerton.
You look absolutely exquisite, as always.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I hope there's room on your dance card
for the two of us.
I believe there is.
["Second Waltz"
by Dmitri Shostakovich ends]
Jeffries!
Your Grace.
Why is this painting here
and not at Somerset House?
Have you forgotten, sir?
You requested it returned to you,
an endeavor that was no small feat
to arrange, I might add.
[dramatic music plays]
Mr. Bridgerton.
Come in, come in.
Thank you.
I do not know what I <span style="style2">was expecting,
but it surely was not this.
Oh, simply a gathering
of like-minded souls.
Here, let me show you
what I've been working on.
They speak of war abroad as if
it will distract from inequities at home.
They do not need a war to be distracted.
Why, this Whistledown's enough
to turn their eyes
from the needs of ordinary people.
[Henry] What do you think?
[Benedict sighs]
Hmm.
It's a far cry
from Somerset House, I must say.
I shall take that as a compliment.
[both chuckle]
And I must say, I'm truly jealous.
Is this your life?
There are advantages
to being the second-born.
Heirs have the responsibility.
-Second sons have the fun.
-[both chuckle]
So…
why not go have some fun?
[exhales slowly]
[singing "Belle nuit, ô nuit d'amour"
in French]
[guests chattering quietly]
[Violet] Anthony?
Anthony.
This is Miss Addington,
the Earl of Lindsay's niece.
-Pleasure.
-Mm.
[Violet chuckles] There, you see?
[chuckles awkwardly]
Quite the affair, Lady Trowbridge.
You have such, uh…
[chuckles] …striking taste.
What a compliment, Lady Featherington,
especially from you.
[Lady Featherington] Mm.
Philippa, should you not be
on the dance floor with Mr. Finch?
[Philippa sobs]
Dry your eyes.
Such constant commotion
with this one, Mama.
-Mr. Finch won't so much as meet my eye.
-[Prudence scoffs]
Papa told him something, and now…
I loved him. [sobs]
Whatever did you say to Mr. Finch?
He may not be a lord,
but he's perfectly suitable,
and Phillipa has no other suitors.
Then we shall wait until next season.
With two others unwed?
They can all wait until next season,
as far as I'm concerned.
Could you truly wish
to embarrass me further tonight?
I would advise against it.
What are you doing in my room?
Oh… Uh…
Mama asked me to retrieve
the latest copy of Lady Whistledown.
She wanted to count how many times Daphne
and Prince Friedrich had been mentioned.
The viscountess is at the Trowbridge ball.
She did not seem particularly pleased
about Prince Friedrich.
[chuckles nervously]
Why do you have them,
all of these Whistledowns?
Must I explain myself to you?
Yes…
you must.
After all, I am a Bridgerton,
so therefore your mistress.
I wiped your bottom
when you were in leading strings,
and I… I do not appreciate your tone.
I asked you once, and I ask again,
what are you doing in my room, Eloise?
Thinking perhaps <span style="style2">you are Lady Whistledown.
[laughing]
Or… if not you,
then perhaps another servant type.
Are you not meant to be the smart one?
-I beg your pardon?
-[laughs]
You believe a servant would ever have
the time to be Lady Whistledown,
with all the work we must do?
-[laughing continues]
-[Eloise chuckles awkwardly]
You believe I would be working for you
if I had all the money Whistledown does?
-[Eloise sighs ironically]
-Oh! Oh!
Oh, it hurts. [laughing continues]
Get out.
[guests chattering]
Our host looks a bit fussy.
Do you think if he goes to bed,
we all have to leave?
[Penelope chuckles]
It's lucky the lady produced an heir
before the old earl croaked, no?
Lucky, indeed.
But do you not think
the boy bears a passing resemblance
to Lady Trowbridge's footman?
Penelope!
What a barb!
I've tried to get in front
of Miss Thompson all night.
Surely she cannot be interested
in Lord Rutledge, can she?
I think the only thing
Miss Thompson is interested in
is a swift rescue, indeed.
I believe you are right.
Oh, Colin, I did not mean--
Another?
[chuckles] I do believe a third dance
would be considered improper, my lord.
You need not continue
to prove your virtue to me, my girl.
There are other things
a man looks for in a wife.
Miss Thompson. A dance?
Are you well recovered, Miss Thompson?
Oh, yes. Um, I was quite ill.
And what a suspicious illness
you came down with.
It seems to have manifested
as a walking spittle factory
with very large teeth.
-Am I the only one who can see it?
-Alas, I can as well.
But spin me away,
and perhaps I shall recover.
[both laughing]
They appear to be enjoying themselves.
Yes. My brother Colin certainly knows
how to make things memorable.
Well, perhaps I may do the same.
I know we've only known each other
a short time, Miss Bridgerton,
but from the moment
I laid eyes on you, I, uh--
-Ah! There you are.
-Here I am, Your Highness.
As I was saying,
some in Prussia believe I have run away,
but the truth is I left
to find someone to start a life with.
-To have a family with.
-[gasps]
[gasps]
And so I find myself left
with one question to ask.
-Miss Bridgerton--
-I need a moment.
To refresh myself, Your Highness.
[breathes nervously]
Miss Bridgerton, are you yet engaged?
You must set me up with one
of those brothers I hear the prince has.
Do watch where you are flying, angel.
[exhales nervously]
[gasping]
[grunts loudly, panting]
[Simon] Miss Bridgerton.
[gasps]
What are you doing here?
-I thought you were leaving London.
-I was. I am.
-I came to say goodbye.
-To whom?
-To you.
-Your goodbye is wholly unnecessary.
We are not friends.
We never were friends,
as you made abundantly clear.
-And I am sorry for that.
-Please, do not apologize.
I shall not be led once more
by you from this direction to that.
You are my friend. You are not my friend.
You are a rake. You are not a rake.
-You are sorry--
-I am sorry.
That is very well.
But you should know that your apology
has absolutely no effect on my life,
nor does your leaving London.
I am marrying the prince.
I shall be very happy, indeed.
Will you be? Happy?
Why would I not be?
Prince Friedrich is kind…
and adoring…
and he knows what he wants.
He is a good man,
and he will make a wonderful father.
And so you truly believe him
the best man for you?
How dare you question my choices?
They are my choices to make, not yours.
I do not question your choice
to rake across the continent,
forlorn and alone.
I do not have to explain myself to you.
I do not owe you anything.
He is perfect for me.
I am going to be princess!
Are you going to say anything?
Well, then, leave.
[groans]
Very well.
[Simon] Miss Bridgerton.
Miss Bridgerton.
Miss Bridgerton!
Come back to the party.
Stop walking!
-Stop following me.
-It is not safe out here.
-I forbid you to go any further.
-You cannot tell me what to do.
[Simon] Daphne…
Will you not listen?
[Daphne breaths tremulously]
My most sincere apologies.
[Daphne panting]
[Simon] I…
I…
[Daphne gasping] Oh!
[both grunting, moaning]
[Daphne gasps]
Bastard!
-[Anthony grunts]
-Anthony!
[Daphne gasps]
You will marry her.
-What?
-[Anthony] Immediately.
We can only hope
no one saw you take such liberties,
and my sister
is saved further mortification.
-You will marry her!
-Brother!
[panting] I cannot marry her.
You have defiled her innocence,
and now you refuse her hand?
I knew you were a rake, Hastings,
never thought a villain.
I cannot marry her.
Then you leave me no choice.
I must demand satisfaction.
A duel? Anthony, you cannot--
He dishonors you, sister.
He dishonors you and me
and the very Bridgerton name.
I have misjudged you, indeed.
You have duped us both,
but I shall not see
my sister pay for my own misdeeds.
-We will settle this as gentlemen.
-I understand.
I shall see you at dawn.
I do not understand.
You would rather die than marry me?
I am truly sorry.
[Anthony] We need to go, Daph,
before anyone should see us.
[distorted sigh]
[distorted heartbeat]
[distorted laughing, chattering]
[distortion ends]
[Violet] Champagne!
It sounds like "sham" and "pain."
It is quite amusing, really. [laughs]
Our sister has a headache.
I am taking her home.
-See to Mother, will you?
-Daphne, you look unwell.
Did you catch a chill in the garden?
[bristles brushing]
Hmm.
-You have great potential.
-It's nothing.
Though,
for such a staunch critic of others,
you certainly lack
a clear eye for your own work.
It's the lines.
Not what they're supposed to be.
Take the compliment, Bridgerton.
There is no expectation or judgment here.
You left all of that back in Mayfair.
[Benedict chuckles]
You can feel free to be yourself here…
if that's what you should like.
It's what works for me, at least.
And I haven't been dissatisfied
with my lines in… well, quite some time.
[Benedict chuckles]
-Well, I've done worse, I suppose, really.
-Mm. Fair enough.
I seem to have enjoyed myself
too much this evening.
I should be on my way.
[exhales deeply] As you wish.
But know you are welcome back any time
for practice or even conversation.
[both laughing]
I'll see you out.
I knew something was amiss
when he insisted we keep Miss Thompson,
but did I quarrel with him? No.
I did what I was told, I did my best.
But getting rid
of my dear Philippa's one and only suitor…
Under no circumstances. Intolerable man!
Guard the door.
What exactly
are you hoping to find, ma'am?
I shan't know that,
Mrs. Varley, until I find it.
Pen, he is kind and funny
and a surprisingly accomplished dancer.
And, well, I'm sure you've seen him
with the small Bridgertons.
He will be a wonderful father.
[chuckles lightly]
Surely, though,
Colin is a tad young for marriage.
You do need someone
who will propose soon.
But that is why
Mr. Bridgerton is so perfect.
Did you see the way he rescued me tonight?
He's not like the other young men
who play games and guard their affections.
He is eager.
Pen, I believe he will propose soon.
-I shan't have to marry Rutledge.
-[forced chuckle]
Oh, I am sorry.
Am I keeping you awake with all this talk?
Yes, I do feel sleep coming over me.
But, Pen…
the best part is,
when we wed,
I'll be able to stay in town.
And since you and Eloise are so close,
we will all practically be sisters.
Imagine that.
[exhales joyously]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sobbing breaths]
[light tapping]
I have a theory.
[strained chuckle]
-Eloise, it is quite late.
-A good theory about Lady Whistledown.
I thought she had to be a servant,
but I was wrong, quite wrong.
Because who truly has
the time and means to be that remarkable?
Who would be invited
to all of the parties,
able to hear things unnoticed by others?
Perhaps we can discuss it tomorrow.
Lady Whistledown is someone free
and unencumbered by society.
She is a single woman of means.
Better yet, she is a widow,
who would be invited to all of the events
but not paid any attention.
While you were at the ball--
Eloise, I do not care!
People have real problems,
mature problems,
problems that have nothing to do
with the secret identity
of some silly writer.
And you are so mature now?
Well, I am of age.
I am out in society.
Therefore, I have more important,
mature things to worry about.
-Like what?
-Like marriage.
-You do not care about marriage.
-What if I do?
I cannot expect you to understand.
Not everyone can be a pretty Bridgerton.
Eloise, I did not--
Eloise, wait!
Thank you, Humboldt.
No need to send anyone up.
I want you to know
I am not angry with you.
I do not blame you for what transpired.
Do not treat me like a child.
I did this.
-He took advantage of you.
-No less than I took liberties with him.
You do not understand.
I should have protected you better.
I knew his true nature from the start.
You think that just because I am a woman,
I am incapable of making my own choices?
Is that it, brother?
Do you even care
that Simon has dishonored me, as you say,
or is it your own male pride
that you seek to satisfy?
-You are to go on up to bed.
-You cannot duel him.
It is illegal, to name but one reason.
You could both be arrested,
let alone killed.
-There must be another way.
-What would you have me do?
I do not take this decision lightly,
but this is the way
things are handled amongst gentlemen.
-If this were to become known--
-I could live with that.
What I could not live with
is the duke's death on my hands.
Nor yours, however tempting
that may be at this very moment.
It is more than just your honor at stake.
It is your sisters', too,
the entire family name.
It has been decided.
Oh, this is madness!
What is it?
You and I need to talk.
Daphne, bed.
[door slams]
[panting deeply, growls]
I will need you to stand as my second.
What if you get yourself killed?
Then the title and estates
will pass to you.
-And if you kill Hastings?
-I shall have to leave the country.
You'll be head of the family
in every way that matters.
[muffled chuckling]
[Colin] Of course not.
You are clearly sober.
[Violet laughs]
And I'm sober enough to know
when you're being impertinent.
-Good night, dear.
-Good night, Mother.
Come here.
Good God. Did someone die?
[clattering]
What are you doing?
I find myself
in rather desperate need of a drink.
And this was the only place
you could find one?
Are you not supposed
to be on a ship by now?
Change of plans.
For brandy this good, you need
to actually tell me what is going on.
I am to meet Anthony Bridgerton at dawn.
Whatever the insult, apologize,
and he will surely be a forgiving man.
Not when it comes to his sister.
Exactly how insulted was she?
[exhales tremulously]
I shall need another
if I am to be your second.
-I cannot let you.
-You cannot stop me.
[tense music plays]
I believe you may have strayed too far
from home tonight.
Siena, please.
We cannot be together. I know that now.
This world shall not permit it.
But what if we were to find ourselves
in another situation,
at a place
where you and I might be accepted,
with none of the shame nor recriminations
that this society grants us.
Would you have me then?
You talk in dreams, my lord,
and yet you deprive me
the luxury of sleep.
I duel at dawn.
An affair of honor?
If I live to see sunrise, I am free…
free of society, free of these rules,
the very ones that keep us apart.
We could go together,
away from all this, Siena.
My apologies.
I've taxed your patience
for the last time.
[Anthony moans]
[both breathing heavily]
[both grunting, moaning]
[sighs]
-Wh-- What are you doing in here?
-Hush.
I found your ledgers,
hidden under old newspapers, no less.
[exhales tremulously]
I know of every transaction…
every financial account.
-Y-- You do not know--
-I know…
everything.
I know about your gambling.
I know about your debts.
I know that you have spent all our money.
-I shall not--
-Including our girls' dowries!
Is that not why you rejected
that perfectly acceptable Mr. Finch
for our dear Philippa?
Is it not why we continue
to keep Miss Thompson in our home?
You owe her father too.
So the question
certainly is not what I know!
[sighs]
The question is…
what are <span style="style2">you going to do about it?
-[sobs]
-My lord?
-[weeping]
[sniffs loudly]
Archibald…
I've have failed you!
I've-- I've--
I have failed our daughters!
I…
I do not know what to do.
[sobbing] Portia…
I don't know what to do.
[weeping, sniffing]
[tense music plays]
[kisses]
[tense music continues]
-Where have they gone?
-Daph…
-Tell me where this duel takes place.
-Why would I do that?
-So that I may prevent it from happening.
-Hastings has done you a grave dishonor.
-Surely you wish to see him pay.
-Not with his life.
It will not come to that.
The duke will remember his honor
once he finds himself
on the deadly end of a pistol.
And if he does not?
They will both do the gentlemanly thing
and fire their pistols wide.
Allow them to bring this ugly business
to a conclusion themselves.
[groans] Do you know how many times
I have heard that said?
To leave the men to their business
and to not concern myself
with such weighty affairs,
whose affairs are my future, my family.
Anthony is too angry to fire wide,
and Simon is too stubborn to yield.
You did not see them in that garden.
No, I did not,
and neither did anyone else.
You should be happy
that no one saw anything.
Daphne, you look unwell.
Did you catch a chill in the garden?
Only, someone did see.
Cressida Cowper.
Colin, you must tell me.
Where have they gone?
Doctor, I appreciate
your attendance and discretion.
You have my blunt?
Very well.
Try not to go dying while I am present.
If the goal is merely to wound,
where should my brother aim?
You think you have the skill
to guide the path of a moving bullet?
Then you are either a fool
or the king's finest marksman.
Which is it?
[horses neighing]
I have one last matter
to discuss with you.
You have already provided
ample instruction.
Contact the solicitor
and safeguard our sisters' dowries.
An additional task.
In the top drawer of my desk,
you shall find the name of a lady.
If I die, you must ensure
she is provided for. Do you swear?
-Benedict, do--
-I swear.
-Brother--
-That is all.
-Is there anything you need from me?
-My affairs are in order.
[tense music intensifies]
For what it is worth, I am sorry.
Your apology is worth nothing to me.
[pistols cocking]
Ready!
[tense music crescendos]
-Stop!
-[gunshot]
-[horse whinnies]
-Daphne! [gasps]
Sister!
Sister! Stand aside!
-Oh, good God.
-[Daphne panting]
Are you hurt? Tell me!
I am perfectly well,
no thanks to you idiots.
-What are you playing at?
-Says the man who just shot at me!
You rode into the middle of a duel!
I require a moment with the duke.
-Daphne--
-I require a moment with the duke.
Make it brief.
You should not have come.
My mind's not changed.
It must.
If not for your sake, then mine.
Simon, we were seen.
Cressida Cowper
witnessed us in the garden.
She knows.
It is not merely your own life
that hangs in the balance now.
If you do not marry me,
I shall be ruined.
Daphne, I cannot.
Did you not hear me?
Someone knows what we have done,
someone who will surely talk.
What possible reason could you have
to condemn me to shame and reproach?
Do you truly…
Do you truly hold me in such low regard?
It is because I regard you so highly
that I cannot marry you.
I know you do not love me,
but I never thought
you could despise me so.
Daphne…
You must know, if we were to wed…
I can never give you children.
It is your dream to be a mother,
is it not?
To have a household
full of love and laughter,
like the one you have known all your life?
You deserve nothing less.
You deserve everything your heart desires.
But I cannot provide it for you.
Nor could I ever ask such a sacrifice.
Please, Daphne, for your own sake…
you must stand aside…
and let your brother finish this.
We must resume
before someone should find us.
There will be no need to resume.
The duke and I are to be married.